Contoso Pizza Web UI
About the Project
This is a completed tutorial project from the Microsoft Learn course "Create a web UI with ASP.NET Core"
Running the project locally
use dotnet watch run with the project parameter to build, start, and run the project locally
The web application now opens with a custom welcome page.
The boilerplate templates are available, but let's direct attention to the Pizza List page.
Creating a Pizza
Enter the pizza name, select the size, and enter a price.
Notice the page is refreshed with the newly added pizza.
Deleting a pizza
Click the Delete button and notice the pizza is now deleted from the list.
Form Validation
The name and price form fields are required.
Users are required to enter the price within a preset range.
Embedded SQL Database
To make things simple, this project uses an embedded SQL database.
SQL Light is a Visual Studio extension that can be used to view and edit the embedded database.
This extension can currently be downloaded and installed for free from the Visual Studio marketplace.